A Guide to the J. Austin Kerr papers FA1282
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Manuscripts, 1927-1974; 2; 3.21 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes, 4 legal document boxes, and 1 flat file folder
  - Manuscripts by J. Austin Kerr, Numbers 1-39, 1927-1970 (Box 6, Folder 43-45)
    26 - Instrucciones Para La Vacunación Contra La Fiebre Amarilla, June 8, 1938
    27 - What to Bring to Brazil, Janet Kerr, 1940
    28 - Memorandum - Dr. J. A. Kerr and Dr. F. L. Soper - A Hypothetical Explanation of the Epidemiology of Jungle Yellow Fever, June 9, 1940
    29 - Yellow Fever and its Control, March 1941
    30 - Suggestions - Memorandum from Miss Louise Kieninger to the Hospitalization Sub-Committee of the American Society of Rio de Janeiro regarding nursing in the Federal District, March 1942
    Folder 45:
    31 - Memorandum Re: Nursing in Brazil, July 18, 1942
    32 - Yellow Fever Research Service Special Report for the Period July 1, 1941-June 30, 1942 - Copy
    33 - On "Field Investigations" - Draft, Rio, 1942
    34 - Nursing in Brazil, Rio, 1942
    35 - A Theoretical Discussion of How Mice are Immunized, March 1943
    36 - Yellow Fever "B" Thoughts on March 28, 1943
    37 - Narrative Report for January to June 1943
    38 - Memorandum - Further Observations on the Results Obtained Following the Use of the "17DD High" Substrain of 17D Virus as Vaccine, December 1, 1943
    39 - A Review of the Efficacy of Vaccination Against Yellow Fever as Applied in 1938 and 1939 in Brazil, December 1, 1943
  - Manuscripts of J. Austin Kerr, Table of Contents and Index, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - J. Austin Kerr Manuscript Number 159 Entitled The Rise and Fall of Global Malaria Eradication, 1955-1974 (Box 6, Folder 47, Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Manuscripts by J. Austin Kerr, Numbers 42-68, 1944-1959 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    42 - "Jaundice" at Lemoore Army Air Field, May 3, 1944
    43 - A Working Hypothesis Regarding Infective Hepatitis, Or So-Called "Acute Catarrhal Jaundice," as a Virus Disease of World-Wide Distribution and Almost Universal Incidence, J. Austin Kerr, May 6, 1944
    44 - Research Laboratory, Berkeley - Infective Hepatitis in Vacaville, Solano County (California), J.A. Kerr and H. L Wynns, May 8, 1944
    45 - The Working Methods of the Gambiae Eradication Service by J. A. Kerr (Speech read by JAK celebrating the eradication of Anopheles gambiae from Egypt broadcast on Cairo radio), January 4, 1946
    48 - Standard Technic for the Quantitative Hemagglutinin Inhibition Tests with Influenza Virus Pattern Test of Salk - with Chicken Red Cells, February 17, 1949
    49 - Memo to RMT (?) - Subject: Studies on Mengo Virus, May 6, 1951
    50 - Thoughts on a Polio Vaccine, May 5, 1951
    51 - A hypothesis regarding an extra-human reservoir of poliomyelitis virus, May 31, 1951
    52 - Vote of Thanks (Inauguration of Virus Research Centre), February 4, 1953
    53 - Zoology in Medical Research, August 20, 1953
    54 - Virus Research Rotary Club, Poona, September 21, 1953
    55 - Filterable Viruses - Lecture Given at the College of Military Engineering, Kirkee, March 16. 1954
    56 - Status Report on Yellow Fever in Middle America, Pan American Sanitary Bureau, March 1956?
    57 - World Health Day "Destroy Disease-Carrying Insects" - The Last Refuge of Yellow Fever by J. Austin Kerr, April 7, 1956
    58 - Seminario Sobre Cuarentena Internacional, Veracruz, Ver. July 26-28, 1956 - La Fiebre Amarilla Como Problema Sanitario Internacional
    59 - Status of Yellow Fever in Middle America by J. Austin Kerr, 1956
    60 - Manual of Operations for an Aedes Aegypti Eradication Service, Part Two Manuals of Instruction, Edition of March 1957, Pan American Sanitary Bureau (Part I was never prepared)
    61 - Jungle Yellow Fever and Related Virus Diseases by J. Austin Kerr, Staff Member of the Rockefeller Foundation on loan to the Pan American Sanitary Bureau, October 1, 1957
    62 - AMRO-57 - Studies of Jungle Yellow Fever and Other Virus Infections, Highlights of Seven Weeks in South America, May 1958
    63 - Note on the Use of Complement-Fixation to Identify the Antigen of Yellow Fever Virus in the Blood Serum of Acutely Ill Patients -- A Proposed New Diagnostic Method for Yellow Fever in Man, February 9, 1959
    64 - The Dilemma of Insecticide-Resistance, February 1958
    65 - A Discussion of the Problem Arising When a Species of Anopheles is Found to be Resistant to a Given Insecticide, February 13, 1959
    66 - Resistance of Anopheles Mosquitoes to Insecticides, Summary of remarks by J. Austin Ker, MD at the Third Public Health ICA Technical Conference, Lima, Peru, March 3, 1959
    67 - Instrucciones Suplementaria para determinar la Susceptibilidad o Resistencia de los mosquitos Anopheles Adultos a los Insecticidas por medio del Equipo de Prueba de la Organización Mundial de la Salud para mosquitos adultos, March 1958
    68 - Visualization of the Results of Evaluation Operations, Guatemala City, August 25, 1959
  - The Eradication of Anopheles Gambiae from Egypt by J. Austin Kerr, M.D., Number 46, 1946-1970 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Reports - Gambiae Eradication Service Egypt, Number 47, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 51-53)
    J. Austin Kerr was director July 15, 1944-December 31, 1945, Quarterly Reports, Annual Reports, Appendix
  - Global Medicine Lectures, Number 69, 1960-1965 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    Global Medicine Lectures by JAK on: A-Malaria; B-Yellow Fever Epidemiology; and C-Yellow Fever Control, given annually 1960-1965 at the Walter Reed Army Institute of Research, Washington, D.C., with pertinent correspondence and some supporting documentation
  - Manuscripts by J. Austin Kerr, Numbers 110-132, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 55-56, Box 9, Folder 57-59)
    Folder 55:
    110 - Two master tracings for summarizing field data collected during the "Synoptic Studies" and "ozalid sepia" tracings on which the data for each of the study areas were recorded as they were obtained, 1965
    111 - Spanish translation of "Synoptic studies of Malaria in El Salvador" by Rachou, Lyons, Moura-Lima, and JAK, January 1965
    112 - Memo - Graphic Representation and Visualization of Results of Malaria Case Detection Operations PAHO/ME XYZ, circa February 1965
    113 - Observaciones sobre la vacuna de virus 17D para fiebre amarilla aplicada por escarificación cutánea, Hernando Groot y Augusto Gast-Galvis, February 1965 with comments from January 21, 1971
    114 - A Hard Look at Malaria Eradication Operations by J. Austin Kerr, March 16, 1965
    Folder 56:
    115 - Rejected Manuscript entitled Bio-Assays with Anopheles Albimanus of DDT and Malathion Residues on the Interior Wall Surfaces of Houses in El Salvador, Central America by J. Austin Kerr et al, February 5, 1965
    116 - Malaria prevalence in the Philippines 1961-1964, by quarters, separately for the Attack and Consolidation Phase areas, May 3, 1965 (reflective comments from August 16, 1974)
    Folder 57:
    117 - Evaluation of the results of the operations of the Philippine Malaria Eradication Program (N.M.E.S.) in the nine years 1955-1963. By J. Austin Kerr, dated May 28, 1965
    Folder 58:
    118 - The Philosophy of Malaria Eradication by J. Austin Kerr, 1965
    119 - Malaria Eradication Training Center - Manila, Philippines Special Course in Malaria Entomology, Review of Entomological Problems in the Americas Remarks by J. Austin Kerr on June 9, 1965
    120 - For Use at Session B, June 18, 1965(?), Research - Outline, Four Resurrections of Research by J. Austin Kerr
    121 - A New Procedure for Visualizing the Results of Malaria Case Detection Operations by J. Austin Kerr, June 28, 1965
    121A - Sequential Changes in Norms for Malaria Case Detection in a Malaria Eradication Operation by J. Austin Kerr, July 13, 1965
    122 - The Seven Deadliest Sins of a National Malaria Eradication Service, July 29, 1965
    123 - Paper on the Use of the Ratio Scale to Visualize the Results of Malaria Eradication Operations, June 11, 1965
    Folder 59:
    124 - Appraisal of the Malaria Eradication Training Center, Manila by J. Austin Kerr, November 1965, supporting documents attached
    125 - A "Working Paper" on The Need for a Field Demonstration Area of the METC, Manila by J. Austin Kerr - November 10, 1965
    126 - Memo - Recommendations regarding the Field Training Area of the Malaria Eradication Training Center/Manila, November 17, 1965
    127 - Comments on the Report of the Malaria Eradication Services/Philippines, FY 1965, December 1, 1965
    128 - Christmas message from the Janet and J. Austin Kerr, 1965, Manila, Philippines
    129 - Comments on the 1964 Evaluation on the Viet Nam Eradication Project, J. Austin Kerr, April 26, 1965, Manila
    130 - Graphic Summary of Malaria Prevalence in Seven Provinces of Viet Nam, 1962-1965, August 1965
    131 - Suggestions for a Malaria Control Program by the Government of Viet Nam - First Draft, dated October 24, 1965
    132 - Memo - Re-evaluation of the malaria situation in Laos as per AID to 78 to Manila, dated July 24, 1965
  - Appendix Z to Manuscript #117, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 60)